



DHIRAJ PARASMAL SANCHETI.

Vighnahar Society, Building No- 13, Flat no - 16, Sector – 19, Airoli, Navi Mumbai

(+91-9922556161. ⊠ sancheti.dhiraj@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE:

Seeking challenging assignments in internetworking & Telecommunication with a growth oriented organisation.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

I am a Computer science Engineer graduate with over 2 year work experience as Network as well information security engineer.

I have thorough knowledge of network as well as network security. Currently, I am working in Paladion Networks Pvt. Ltd as a Information Security engineer.

My technical abilities are complemented by sound communication and user interaction abilities.

AREA OF EXPERTISE:

- → A focused networking professional with certification (CCNA) with a consistent academic record.
- → Sound & practical Knowledge of TCP/IP, IPv4.
- → Monitoring all type of Network.
- → RIP, OSPF, EIGRP.
- → Configuration of IPv4 & subsequent backbone routing as per customer's specific requirements.
- → Configuration of routers, switches, hubs, modems and other networking devices.
- → Installation, maintenance & configuring of Cisco Routers, Switches. (Access list).
- → Identifies and tests vulnerabilities as well as conducts research in areas of information security and network security.
- → Analyses Information Security incidents.
- → Maintains firewall, network security, intrusion detection and virus protection.
- → Venerability Assessment and Penetration Testing.
- → IP Addressing, Subnetting, Services and Network Management features such as NAT.
- → Maintaining Firewall and network Security.

EDUCATION:

- → B.E. (Computer) (60.86%) from SNJB'S KBJ COE (Chandwad) under Pune University.
- → HSC (1st class) (68.00%) from K.B.H Jr. College, Malegaon under the Nashik Board.
- → SSC (1st class) (71.46%) from Kakani Vidyalaya, Malegaon under Nashik Board.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

WAF	LOG analysis, Rule creation, Policies Creation
Routing	Static and Default routing, EIGRP, OSPF, OSPF with multiple areas.
Security	Firewall, Access List, Access port.
Firewall	LOG analysis, Rule creation, Policies Creation

EXPERIENCE:

From February 2013 to July 2013 Glucotech (P) Ltd.) as a Technical support Engineer.

→ Our Jobs and Responsibilities

- Configuring and working with DHCP.
- Managing Internal Networks.
- Working with NAT.
- Also providing support to Access layer switches.

From July 2013 to March 2014 Comnet Solution (P) Ltd. (Client Side at WNS Global Services (P) Ltd. Pune) as a Technical (Network) support Engineer.

→ Our Jobs and Responsibilities

- Configuring and working with DHCP.
- Monitoring all types of Network.
- Working with LAN, VLAN, and VTP.
- Also providing support to CISCO Access layer switches as well as IP phones.

From April 2014 to Oct 2014 Vodafone UK Ltd. on the Payroll of Mindlance Pvt Ltd as Network Engineer.

→ Our Jobs and Responsibilities

- Application support for various applications such as Witness contact viewer, Cisco Webview, Web Observer, NU Soft-phone, Cisco Agent Desktop.
- Provide onsite support to L3 team for high priority problem resolution and to carry out major network change activities.
- Basic Network Security.
- Escalating link failures to respective Service Providers.
- Troubleshooting routers, L2 / multilayer switches and Cisco IP Phones for any kind of hardware or software failure at customer sites.
- Maintaining Information Security With ArcSight.
- Monitoring all types of network.
- Daily network operations, maintenance and troubleshooting on site related network hardware and software application. Application includes Cisco Web view, Witness contact viewer (voice recording application), and Soft phone.
- Maintaining 6500 Distribution switch.
- Network Security & Firewall.
- Information Security & VAPT.

From October 2014 to till Date Paladion Networks Pvt. Ltd as Information Security Engineer.

→ Our Jobs and Responsibilities

- Managing WAF, Firewall and other Network security Devices.
- Creation rules and policies in firewall and IPS.
- Policies enforcement into WAF, IPS, Firewall.
- Help systems team in setting up and configuring machines, networks, firewalls etc using ArcSight or different tool.
- Securely Facilitation of Vulnerability Scans, Penetration testing etc.
- Manage the daily, weekly, quarterly, annual compliance activities like log reviews, privilege reviews, firewall reviews, security patches to machines etc
- Network Security, Firewall Security as well as Information Security.
- Handles the tasks of diagnosing and resolving technical problems in internal resources
- Plans as well as prepares detail practices and procedures on various technical processes
- Designs and configures network security and enterprise network monitoring.
- Identifies and tests vulnerabilities as well as conducts research in areas of information security and network security.
- Analyses Network security incidents as well as Information Security incidents.
- Maintains firewall, network security, intrusion detection and virus protection.
- Management of Intrusion detection systems (IDS/IPS), Firewall, VPN, and other security.
- Vulnerability Assessment for Audits, Penetration Testing, Web Application Assessment, Security Audits, Forensics, Configuration audits, WAF.
- Knowledge of ArcSight, McAfee Security, VA Tools.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION & CERTIFICATION.

- → CCNA Certified (CISCO ID- CSCO12561750)
- → CEH V8 Certified. (CEH ID- ECC89765654148)

COMPUTER PREFICIENCY.

→ Areas of Interest : Information Security, Network Security, Application Security.

STRENGTH.

- → I believe in maintaining high standard of work.
- → Good Team Work With Positive Approach.
- → I believe in sincerity and dedication in the execution of the work given to me.

PERSONAL DETAIL:

Name : Dhiraj Sancheti. Father's Name : Parasmal Sancheti. Mother's Name : Chandrakala Sancheti.

DOB: 28 October.Blood Group: O+veMarital Status: SingleGender: MaleLanguages known: English, Hindi and MarathiNationality: Indian

I hereby declare that the information given above are true to the best of my knowledge and belief, If get an opportunity to work in your esteemed concern I will work to the best of my ability With honesty.

Place – Mumbai.

Date-